Stephanie Japs

Web Developer

Stephanie Japs

612.306.3237 stephjaps@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-japs/

https://github.com/minnesotanice/

http://www.stephjaps.com/

Statement

Experienced at working on projects from initial idea and development phase, performing all design/architecture work and delivering the completed product. Proven track record of excelling at learning new technologies and applying them to develop clean and well-structured code.

Technologies

HTML, SASS/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ColdFusion

Programs

Visual Studio Code, Git, Photoshop, Illustrator

Experience

NewBay Media / Front End Web Developer

AUGUST 2014 - PRESENT, MINNEAPOLIS, MN

Coded a third party web design into a pixel perfect, responsive site with ColdFusion, HTML5 and CSS. (www.AV-iQ.com)

Set up SASS to easily customize colors and compress CSS for hundreds of product catalogs.

Create interactive features using jQuery and Javascript.

Write and document code that is well organized and reusable.

Collaborate with other developers to create effective solutions.

Mentor students to be quality Front End Developers.

Use Git for version control.

Prototype new website features with Photoshop, Illustrator and Fireworks in conjunction with manipulating the DOM.

Create email templates for dynamic content that display well in a variety of email clients.

All duties listed below from Web Designer position.

InfoComm International / Front End Web Developer

OCTOBER 20010 - AUGUST 2014, MINNEAPOLIS, MN

AV-iQ was a division of InfoComm International until it was bought by NewBay Media in August of 2014. See job description above.

InfoComm International / Web Designer

OCTOBER 2004 - OCTOBER 2010, MINNEAPOLIS, MN

Make companies product catalogs look and function seamlessly in client website designs using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ColdFusion.

Prototype new website features with Photoshop, Illustrator and Fireworks in conjunction with manipulating the DOM.

Create email templates for dynamic content that display well in a variety of email clients.

Create banner ads.

Optimize sites for all browsers.

InfoComm International / Graphics Editor-Project Manager

APRIL 2001 - OCTOBER 2004, MINNEAPOLIS, MN

In addition to photo editing duties for the Photo Editor position described below, I created banner ads and managed new development projects. I occasionally helped the Web Designer before transitioning to that job as a full time position.

Education

University of Minnesota / Coding Boot Camp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, and Node.

2018, Saint Paul, Minnesota

Metropolitan State University / Bachelor's Degree, Self-Designed Degree in Computer Arts

1999, Saint Paul, Minnesota